Guide to the Will Parry Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Will Parry papers
approximately 1908-2013
1977-1981
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
5316
Parry, Will$c(Labor activist)
1.79 cubic ft 3 boxes
Papers of a labor activist in King County, Washington
Will Parry was a labor activist in King County, Washington. From 1977 to 1978, Parry and Ross Rieder, of the Washington State Labor Council, organized King County unions to assist workers in picketing automobile dealerships. The strikes were in reaction to a growing trend among the dealerships to open their shops to non-union work. Parry and Ross paired again to organize the Washington State delegation of union members and supporters for Solidarity Day -- a rally against the Reagan administration initiated by the AFL-CIO Executive Council and held in Washington, D.C., on September 19, 1981.
Contains strike bulletins, clippings, notes, and photographs from the auto trades strike in King County, Washington, 1977-1978. Also contains newsletters, clippings, photographs, and related items about Solidarity Day in 1981, and the United States labor movement's protest against budget cuts in social programs by the Reagan administration. Also contains newsletters, clippings, photographs and correspondence from his early life, work life and travel.
Organized into 2 accessions.
Accession No. 5316-001, Will Parry papers, 1977-1981
Accession No. 5316-002, Will Parry papers, circa 1908-2013
Open to all users, but access to portions of the collection is restricted. Contact Special Collections for details.
Parry, Will$e(Labor activist)$vArchives; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Labor leaders$zWashington (State)$zKing County$vArchives; Strikes and lockouts$xAutomobile industry$zWashington (State)$zKing County; Labor disputes$zWashington (State)$zKing County; Federal aid to human services$zUnited States; Demonstrations$zWashington (D.C.); Labor leaders$zWashington (State)$zKing County; Picketing$zWashington (State)$zKing County$vPhotographs; Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor; Labor Unions; Labor History; Washington (State); Photographs; Newsletters; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Photographs; notes; ephemera; writings
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Will Parry papers, 1977-1981; 5316-001; Parry, Will; .21 cubic foot 1 box
  Contains strike bulletins, clippings, notes, and photographs from the auto trades strike in King County, Washington, 1977-1978. Also contains newsletters, clippings, photographs, and related items about Solidarity Day in 1981, and the United States labor movement's protest against budget cuts in social programs by the Reagan administration. Also contains newsletters, clippings, photographs and correspondence from his early life, work life and travel.
  Arranged in multiple series:
  Auto trades strike
  Solidarity Day
  The papers are open to all users.
  Received from Will Parry via Ross Rieder, October 3, 2001.
  - Auto trades strike
    - Fact sheet, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Boycotting lists, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Strike bulletins
      - Reports, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/3)
      - The Volunteer Picket, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/4)
      - Miscellaneous, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Newspaper: The Scanner, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Writing: "Strike Effort Keeps Growing", 1978 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Writings of others, 1966, 1978 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Photographs, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/9)
      Includes 14 black-and-white and color photographs of picketers and picketing sites. Also includes 2 black-and-white photographs of strike food bank.
    - Notes, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Ephemera, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Clippings, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Solidarity Day
    - Fact sheets, 1981 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - General correspondence, 1981 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Notices, 1981 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Calendars, 1981 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - News releases, 1981 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Lists/rosters, 1981 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Resolutions, 1981 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Newsletters
      - Jobs & Justice, the Washington State Campaign for Solidarity Day, 1981 (Box-folder 1/20)
      - Miscellaneous, 1981 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Speeches and writings of others, 1981 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Photograph, 1981 (Box-folder 1/23)
      8 x 10-inch black-and-white photograph of a group of Washington State unionists at Solidarity Day, Washington, D.C., in front of a hotel.
    - Notes, 1981 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Ephemera, 1981 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Clippings, 1981 (Box-folder 1/26)
- Will Parry papers, circa 1908-2013; 5316-002; 1.58 cubic ft (2 boxes)
  Materials documenting Will Parry's life, probably assembled for his 90th birthday celebration in April of 2010. Materials include newsclippings of articles written by Parry, photographs, birth certificates, and material on the Parry family. Records document Parry's activism on behalf of labor rights and progressive political causes. Also included is a 1963 reprint of the June 7, 1889 Seattle PI issue on the Seattle fire.
  Open to all users, but access to portions of the collection is restricted. Contact Special Collections for details.
  Imogene Williams, partner of Will Parry, 7/1/2014
  - Personal papers, circa 1908-2013 (Box 1)
  - Reprint of June 7, 1889 Seattle PI issue, 1963 (Box:oversize 2)